<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[mattgillingham.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://gillygize.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gillygize.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-22T20:34:19+09:00</updated>
  <id>http://gillygize.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matthew Gillingham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://gillygize.github.com/blog/2012/06/22/setting-up-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-22T18:25:00+09:00</updated>
    <id>http://gillygize.github.com/blog/2012/06/22/setting-up-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent the last past two days working on setting up my website.  My first effort involved using <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> and the second involved using <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, a package which is built on top of Jeykll and provides some extra plugins, a new deployment system, and a built-in template.</p>

<p>My main goal was to take advantage of the cool auto-generating features of <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>, which provides free hosting and an automated system which can turn a collection of text files created in writer-friendly text formats like Textile or Markdown into a static HTML website.  The site is regenerated after a git push.</p>

<p>It is nice in practice, but I haven&#8217;t hand-written HTML and CSS in a while, and getting all of the content to display the way that I wanted it took some effort.  In Jekyll, the layout code more or less has to be done from stratch.  In Octopress, there is an attractive default theme with a number of nice features, but modifying it to avoid looking exactly like everyone else&#8217;s Octopress blog takes some time.  Rather than using CSS, it uses a CSS-generating system called <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">SASS</a> to generate the layouts.  If you have some understanding of CSS, it is not so hard to make pick up; I have been outside of the web developer world for a while and found there were a number of things I needed to learn at once.</p>

<p>All said and done, my goal of putting up a quick website turned out to be not particularly quick, but this is the kind of system that a web designer might like, and that gives me a chance to see what has been going on in that field recently.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
